A Guide to the Papers of W. Ralph Singleton, 1940-1980
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series V: Atomic Energy Laboratory (Kasetsart University)
  - Atomic Energy Laboratory (Kasetsart University) - International Atomic Energy Agency 1965 (Box 14)
  - Atomic Energy Laboratory (Kasetsart University) - International Rice Mutation Breeding Symposium, Bangkok, Thailand 1965 (Box 14)
  - Atomic Energy Laboratory (Kasetsart University) - In Transit 1965 1965 (Box 14)
  - Atomic Energy Laboratory (Kasetsart University) - Kirby, Anna C. 1965 (Box 14)
  - Atomic Energy Laboratory (Kasetsart University) - Lectures 1965 (Box 14)
  - Atomic Energy Laboratory (Kasetsart University) - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1965, n.d. (Box 14)
  - Atomic Energy Laboratory (Kasetsart University) - Notes n.d. (Box 14)
  - Atomic Energy Laboratory (Kasetsart University) - Symposium Papers (unknown) n.d. (Box 14)
- Series VI: Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1965-1969 (Box 14)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Field Book 1966 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Miscellaneous 1966-1970 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Zirkle, Conway 1967 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Membership 1967-1968 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1967-1968 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Virginia Division of Forestry, Chestnuts 1967-1970 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Data (Field Fertilizers) 1968 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Correspondence, Data (Expenses) 1968-1970 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Correspondence, Chestnut 1968-1971 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Annual Meeting 1969 1969 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Chestnut Reprints and Xeroxes 1969 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Chestnut Symposium 1969 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Correspondence, Colonial varieties 1969 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Miscellaney 1969 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Strauss, Robert W. 1969 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Stronghold Inc., Symposium on Chestnuts 1969 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Correspondence, Chestnut 1969-1971 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Correspondence, Annual Meeting 1970 (Box 15)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Correspondence, Chestnut 1970, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Correspondence, Chestnut, Stronghold, Inc. 1970 (Box 16)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - General Managers Report, 1970 1970 (Box 16)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Memos and Correspondence, Strauss, Robert 1970 (Box 16)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Correspondence, Strauss, Robert W. 1971 (Box 16)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Correspondence, Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 16)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Correspondence, Chestnut Story "Ernest Christensen Interpretive Park Planner" n.d. (Box 16)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Miscellaneous Correspondence n.d. (Box 16)
  - Accokeek Foundation - National Colonial Farm - Research Notes, "Old Corn Varieties" n.d. (Box 16)
- Series VII: Professional Organizations
  - Professional Organizations Correspondence - American Association for the Advancement of Science 1955-1956 (Box 16)
  - Professional Organizations Correspondence - American Association for the Advancement of Science 1967, 1969 (Box 16)
  - Professional Organizations Correspondence - American Boxwood Society 1973-1978 (Box 16)
  - Professional Organizations Correspondence - American Genetics Association 1963-1967, n.d., 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Professional Organizations Correspondence - American Genetics Association 1968-1969, 3 folders (Box 17)
  - Professional Organizations Correspondence - American Institute of Biological Sciences 1966, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Professional Organizations Correspondence - American Society of Agronomy 1952-1955 (Box 17)
  - Professional Organizations Correspondence - American Society of Naturalists 1954 (Box 17)
  - Professional Organizations Correspondence - Association of S. E. Biologists 1967 (Box 17)
  - Professional Organizations Correspondence - Genetics Society of America 1950-1960, 2 folders (Box 17)
- Series VIII: Speeches and Writings
  - "Harvest Leaves Now" sent to New York Times, October 1945, not used 1945, TMs (Box 17)
  - "Man and the Atom" 1948, Ms (Box 17)
  - "Corn Grass - a possible ancestral type of maize" 1949, TMs (Box 18)
  - "Atomic Energy and Abundance" 1954, TMs (Box 18)
  - "Atomic Energy and Agriculture" - Copy 1954 (Box 18)
  - Comments and Corrections of W. R. Singleton on Proceedings of the Argonne Genetics Conference 1954, TMs (Box 18)
  - "The Contribution of Atomic Energy to Agriculture" 1954 (Box 18)
  - "The Contribution of Radiation Genetics to Agriculture" - Copy 1954, TMs (Box 18)
  - "How Atomic Research Benefits the Farmer" 1954, TMs (Box 18)
  - "The Search for Truth" 1954, TMs (Box 18)
  - Applications of Radioisotopes and Nuclear Radiations in Food and Agriculture, Abstracts from the Geneva Conference (Annotated) 1955 (Box 18)
  - "Biology and Atomic Energy" 1955, TMs (Box 18)
  - "A Cobalt 60 Field Irradiation Machine" 1955, TMs (Box 18)
  - "The Contribution of Radiation Genetics to Crop Improvement" 1955, TMs (Box 18)
  - "Effect of Chronic Gamma Radiation on Somatic Mutations in Maize" 1955, TMs (Box 18)
  - "Mutation Breeding," Atomic Energy and Corn Improvements" 1955, TMss (Box 18)
  - A.A.A.S. Symposium, Tukey, H. B., Correspondence 1955 (Box 18)
  - "The Use of Radiation in Plant Breeding" 1955, TMs (Box 18)
  - "Atomic Energy in Agriculture" 1956, TMs (Box 18)
  - "The Use of Radiation in Plant Breeding" 1956, TMs (Box 18)
  - "The Christian and the Atom" 1957, TMs, w/carbons (Box 18)
  - "The Use of Radiation in Plant Breeding," Corrected Galley Proofs - Duplicate 1957 (Box 18)
  - "Radiation Biology at the University of Virginia 1958, TMs (Box 18)
  - "Search for Truth," Speech Notes 1958 (Box 19)
  - "The Use of Radiation in Plant Breeding" and copies of talk w/corrections 1959, TMs (Box 19)
  - 1960 Volunteer Papers Cornell Symposium Plant and Breeding 1960 (Box 19)
  - "Radiation Plant Breeding with Emphasis on Corn" 1961, TMs (Box 19)
  - Sermons: Gordonsville, Scottsville and Keswick 1961 (Box 19)
  - "Induced Mutations and Plant Breeding," Speech Notes 1962 (Box 19)
  - Review of "Gamma Field Symposium #1" 1962, TMs (Box 19)
  - Singleton Biography Western Trip, August 1962 1962 (Box 19)
  - Symposium on Rice Genetics and Cytogenetics International Rice Research Institute, Philippines 1963, 3 folders (Box 19)
  - "A Allele Necessary for Dilute Color in Horses" and "Use of Radioisotopes in Agriculture" 1965, TMs (carbons) w/corrections (Box 19)
  - "Use of Radioisotopes in Agriculture" 1965, TMs (Box 19)
  - Comments by W. R. Singleton on E. I. Du Pont Botanist; The Beginning of a Tradition amd Review of Genetics is Easy by Philip Goldstein 1967, TMs (Box 19)
  - Singleton Bibliography and Copies of "Use of Radioisotopes in Agriculture" 1967, TMs (Box 20)
  - "The ABC's of Coat Color Inheritance in Horses" and Correspondence 1967-1968, TMs (Box 20)
  - "Atomic Energy and Chestnuts, Can the New Bring Back the Old" 1969, Copy of a Talk (Box 20)
  - Book Reviews of "Comparative Genetics of Coat Color in Mammals" by A. G. Searle and Tms, "The Science of Ionizing Radiation" by Charles C. Thomas 1969, n.d., TMs (Box 20)
  - "Corn-Chestnuts-Colonial Farm" 1969, Talk (Box 20)
  - "Mutants Induced by Treating Maize Seeds with Thermal Neutrons" 1969, TMs (Box 20)
  - Agricultural History, Correspondence 1970 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, Craig, James B. 1970 (Box 20)
  - "Crop Plants in American Agriculture, 1790-1840" 1970, TMs and Drafts (Box 20)
  - Book Review of Zhores A Mendvedev, The Rise and Fall of T. D. Lysenke1971, TMs (Box 20)
  - "Corn and the American Colonists" [1971], TMs (Box 20)
  - Mutation Breeding Workshop 1972 (Box 20)
  - "The Use of Radiation to Produce Blight Resistant Strains of the American Chestnut," also rough draft n.d., TMs (Box 20)
  - Elementary Genetics, 1st Edition, Fan Mail, Reviews, etc. 1962 (Box 20)
  - Elementary Genetics, 1st Edition, Notes and Correspondence 1962 (Box 20)
  - Elementary Genetics, Revision Suggestion Correspondence 1962-1965 (Box 20)
  - Elementary Genetics, 2nd Edition, Correspondence 1964-1969 (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, 1965 Revision, Chapter 1 1965, TMs (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, 2nd Edition, Chapter 2 1965, Ms (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, Comments by Dr. Gerturde Heidenthal on Chapters II and III 1965, TMs (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, 2nd Edition, Permission Letters 1965 (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, 2nd Edition, Research Notes 1965 (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, Asia Edition, Van Nostrand Co. Correspondence 1965-1966 (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, Complimentary Copies 1965, 1967 (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, 2nd Edition, Permission Letters 1966-1967 (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, 2nd Edition, Fan Mail Correspondence 1967 (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, 2nd Edition, Correspondence, Van Nostrand Co. 1967-1970 (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, 2nd Edition, Correspondence Book Requests 1967-1972 (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, 2nd Edition, Book Requests - Van Nostrand Company 1968-1969 (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Chapter 5, Correspondence, Notes and Research Material 1969 (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Chapter 1, Correspondence and Notes 1969 (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Correspondence w/Co-author, Maurice Whittinghill 1969-1970, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Singleton-Whittinghill Contract 1969-1971 (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Correspondence and Notes on Chapter 1 1970 (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Chapter 2, Corrected Proofs (copies) 1970 (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Chapter 3, Correspondence and Notes 1970 (Box 21)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Chapter 6, Correspondence, Notes and Research Material 1970 (Box 22)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Chapter 7, Correspondence and Research Material 1970 (Box 22)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Chapter 9, Copies of Page Proofs w/corrections 1970 (Box 22)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Chapter 13, Correspondence, Notes and Corrected Copies of Page Proofs 1970 (Box 22)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Chapter 14, Corrections and Notes 1970 (Box 22)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Chapter 15, Correspondence and Research Material 1970 (Box 22)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Chapter 16, Notes 1970 (Box 22)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Chapter 17, Correspondence and Research Material 1970 (Box 22)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Chapter 18, Correspondence 1970 (Box 22)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Chapter 19 (old Chapter 16), Correspondence 1970 (Box 22)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Chapter 21, "Evolution" Research Notes 1970 (Box 22)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Revision Notes and Correspondence 1970 (Box 22)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Malcolm MacDonald, Van Nostrand Reinhold Company Correspondence 1970 (Box 22)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Van Nostrand Reinhold Company Reviewer's Comments 1970 (Box 22)
  - Elementary Genetics, 3rd Edition, Correspondence 1970-1971 (Box 22)
  - Copies of Articles and Reviews by Singleton 1930-1977, n.d., 4 folders (Box 22)
  - Miscellany
  - Biological Survey Map n.d. (Box 23)
  - Chestnuts, Lesesne Forest Foundation n.d. (Box 23)
  - Genetics Clippings, Albino Purpoise n.d. (Box 23)
  - Greenhouses n.d. (Box 23)
  - "Humor" n.d. (Box 23)
  - Poetry and Quotations n.d. (Box 23)
  - Miscellany n.d. (Box 23)
  - Printed Material
  - Newspaper Clippings 1935-1954, 1967, n.d., 3 folders (Box 23)
  - Clippings 1936-1974, 7 folders (Box 23)
  - [Oz Nelson] n.d. (Box 23)
  - Scientific American, Annotated Offprints 1948-1964 (Box 24)
  - Xerox Copies (Annotated) n.d. (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous Annotated Research Material 1931-1979, n.d., 5 folders (Box 24)
  - Photographs (Box 24-27)
  - ca. 103 folders 1938-1955, 8 items (Box 24-27)
  - Restricted Material 1955-1969
  - Oversize
  - National Colonial Farm: topographical map 1967
  - National Colonial Farm: topographical worksheet 1967
  - National Colonial Farm: map of development program 1967
  - North Carolina State College of Agriculture, Raleigh, North Carolina: 4 photographs n.d.
  - Brookhaven National laboratory: 5 photographs n.d.
  - Unidentified photograph n.d.